<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc [
  <!ENTITY nbsp    "&#160;">
  <!ENTITY zwsp   "&#8203;">
  <!ENTITY nbhy   "&#8209;">
  <!ENTITY wj     "&#8288;">
]>
<?xml-model href="rfc7991bis.rnc"?>
<!-- <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rfc2629.xslt" ?> -->
<rfc
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        docName="draft-opsawg-havel-digital-map-00"
        category="std"
        ipr="trust200902"
        obsoletes=""
        updates=""
        submissionType="IETF"
        xml:lang="en"
        tocInclude="true"
        sortRefs="true"
        symRefs="true"
        version="3" >
  <front>
    <title abbrev="Digital Map Modelling">Modeling the Digital Map based on RFC8345: Sharing Experience </title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-opsawg-havel-digital-map-00"/>
    <author fullname="Olga Havel" initials="O " surname="Havel">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
      <address>
		<postal>
          <street>Townsend Street, George's Court</street>
          <city>Dublin</city>
          <country>Ireland</country>
        </postal>
        <email>olga.havel@huawei.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>    
	<author fullname="Benoit Claise" initials="B " surname="Claise">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
      <address>
	  	<postal>
          <street>ADD</street>
          <city>ADD</city>
          <country>Belgium</country>
        </postal>
        <email>benoit.claise@huawei.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>	
    <author fullname="Oscar Gonzalez de Dios" initials="O. Gonzalez" surname="de Dios ">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>ADD</street>
          <city>Madrid</city>
          <country>Spain</country>
        </postal>
        <email>oscar.gonzalezdedios@telefonica.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ahmed.Elhassany" initials="A" surname="Elhassany">
      <organization>Swisscom</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Binzring 17</street>
          <city>Zurich</city>
          <code>8045</code>
          <country>Switzerland</country>
        </postal>
        <email>Ahmed.Elhassany@swisscom.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thomas Graf" initials="T" surname="Graf">
      <organization>Swisscom</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Binzring 17</street>
          <city>Zurich</city>
          <code>8045</code>
          <country>Switzerland</country>
        </postal>
        <email>thomas.graf@swisscom.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>	
    <date/>
    <area>General</area>
    <workgroup>OPSAWG</workgroup>
    <abstract>
      <t>
	      This document shares experience in modelling digital map based 
		  on the IETF RFC8345 topology YANG modules and some of its extensions. 
		  It also shares the open issues encountered during the modelling 
		  phase of the Digital Map.
	  </t>
    </abstract>
	<note removeInRFC="true">
      <name>Discussion Venues</name>
      <t>Source for this draft and an issue tracker can be found at
       <eref target="https://github.com/OlgaHuawei"/>.</t>
    </note>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section anchor="intro" >
	  <name>Introduction</name>
      <t>
		The <xref target="RFC8345"/> is a topology based YANG model with many extensions for 
		different technologies and service types. The modelling approach 
		based on <xref target="RFC8345"/> provides the out of box standard IETF based API.
	  </t>
	  <t>
		At the time of writing those lines, there are 60 YANG Modules augmenting <xref target="RFC8345"/>,
		59 IETF and 1 BBF. 8 have maturity level 'ratified', 15 have maturity level 'adopted', 
		21 have maturity level 'latest-approved' and 16 have maturity level 'initial'.
		The up to date information can be found in the YANG Catalogue at 
		<eref target="https://yangcatalog.org/yang-search/impact_analysis/ietf-network-topology@2018-02-26"/>.
	  </t>
	  <t>
		From this long series of IETF RFCs and IETF drafts, we attempted 
		to create a Digital Map PoC, with the following objectives and 
		functionality:
	  </t>
		<ul>
			<li>
			Modelling of digital map entities, relationships, and rules how to 
		    build aggregated entities and relationships. Basically evaluating 
		    how well the different drafts fit together
			</li>
			<li>
			Modelling multiple underlay/overlay layers from L2 to customer 
		    service layer
			</li>
			<li>
			We based our modelling on <xref target="RFC8345"/> and we successfully modelled 
		    the following using this approach:
			</li>
		</ul>
			<t>
			- L2 Network Topology (used <xref target="RFC8944"/>)
			</t>
			<t>
			- L3 Network Topology (used <xref target="RFC8346"/>)
			</t>
			<t>
			- OSPF Routing (to be further aligned with <xref target="I-D.ogondio-opsawg-ospf-topology"/>)
			</t>
			<t>
			- IS-IS Routing (to be further aligned with <xref target="I-D.ogondio-lsr-isis-topology"/>)
			</t>
			<t>
			- BGP Routing
			</t>
			<t>
			- MPLS LDP
			</t>
			<t>
			- MPLS TE Tunnels
			</t>
			<t>
			- SRv6 Tunnels
			</t>
			<t>
			- L3 VPN Services
			</t>
	  <t>
		This draft documents our experience implementing the modelling a 
		real network with the topology YANG modules <xref target="RFC8345"/> model and its 
		extensions. 
	  </t>
	  <t>
		While we progress our Digital Map PoC, we want to share our experience and some open 
		issues encountered.
	  </t>
	  <t>
		During the PoC, we also defined the requirements and verified the 
		PoC approach by demoing it iteratively.
      </t>	  
	  	<section anchor="terminology">
	    <name>Terminology</name>
		<t>
          The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL
          NOT", "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED",
          "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as
          described in BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119"/> <xref target="RFC8174"/>
          when, and only when, they appear in all capitals, as shown here.
		</t>
		<dl>
			<dt>Digital Map Modelling - </dt>
			<dd>
				Modelling the Digital Map using the IETF <xref target="RFC8345"/> approach, 
				by defining the supported network types (layers and sublayers), entity types, 
				entity roles (network, node, tp or link), entity properties and relationships 
				types between entities. 
			</dd>
			<dt>Digital Map - </dt>
			<dd>
				A basis for the Digital Twin that provides a virtual instance 
				of the topological information of the network. It provides the 
				core multi-layer topology model of the digital twin that defines the 
				core topological entities, their role in the network, core 
				properties and relationships both inside each layer and 
				between the layers. It is the basic topological model that is 
				extended with other functional parts of the digital twin and 
				connects them all: configuration, maintenance, assurance 
				(KPIs, status, health, symptoms), traffic engineering, 
				different behaviours, simulation, emulation, mathematical 
				abstractions, AI algorithms, etc 
			</dd>
			<dt>Digital Twin - </dt>
			<dd>
				as defined in <xref target="I-D.irtf-nmrg-network-digital-twin-arch"/>,
				it as 'a virtual instance of a physical system (twin) that is 
				continually updated with the latter’s performance, maintenance 
				and health status data throughout the physical system’s life 
				cycle'.
			</dd>
		</dl>
	  </section>
	</section>
	<section anchor="digital-map-and-digital-twin">
	<name>Digital Map Intro and how it relates to Digital Twin</name>
	  <section anchor="digital-twin">
	  <name>What is Digital Twin?</name>
	  <t>
		The digital twin concepts and the reference architecture of the 
		network digital twin are proposed in the NMRG draft 
		<xref target="I-D.irtf-nmrg-network-digital-twin-arch"/>.
		This draft defines the Digital Twin as 'a virtual instance of 
		a physical system (twin) that is continually updated with 
		the latter’s performance, maintenance and health status data
		throughout the physical system’s life cycle'. 
	  </t>
	  <t>
		The draft <xref target="I-D.irtf-nmrg-network-digital-twin-arch"/>
		also states that a digital twin network can be regarded as an 
		indispensable part of the overall network system and provides 
		a general architecture involving the whole life cycle of 
		physical networks in the future, serving the application of 
		innovative network technologies such as network planning, 
		construction, maintenance and optimization, improving the 
		automation and intelligence level of the network.
	  </t>
	  <t>
		The draft <xref target="I-D.irtf-nmrg-network-digital-twin-arch"/>
		defines the core elements of digital twin – Data, Models,
		Interfaces and Mapping. The digital twin network constructed based
		on the four core technology elements can analyze, diagnose, emulate,
		and control the physical network in its whole life cycle with the 
		help of optimization algorithms, management methods, and expert 
		knowledge
	  </t>
	  </section>
	  <section anchor="digital-map-definition">
	    <name>Digital Map Definition</name>
		<t>
			Digital Map provides the core multi-layer topology model and data
			for the digital twin and connects them to the other digital twin models and data.
		</t>
		<t>			
			The Digital Map Model defines the core topological entities, their role 
			in the network, core properties and relationships both inside each 
			layer and between the layers. 
		</t>
		<t>
			The Digital Map Model is a basic topological model that is extended 
			with other functional parts of the digital twin and connects them 
			all: configuration, maintenance, assurance (KPIs, status, health, 
			symptoms), traffic engineering, different behaviours and actions, 
			simulation, emulation, mathematical abstractions, AI algorithms, etc.
		</t>
		<t>
			The Digital Map Data consists of virtual instances of network and
			service topologies at different layers. The Digital Map provides the
			access to this data via standard API for both read and write, 
			with query capabilities and links to other YANG modules 
			(SAIN, SAP, Inventory, Assets, …) and non-YANG mode. 
		</t>
	  </section>
	  <section anchor="why-digital-map">
	    <name>Why Digital Map?</name>
		<t>
			One of the important requirements for the Digitalization 
			and Digital Twin is to correlate all models and data to 
			topological entities at different layers in the layered twin network. 
			This draft proposes A Digital Map Model as a basis for the 
			Digitalization and Digital Twin. The Digital Map would provide a 
			virtual instance of the topological information of the network, 
			based on this Digital Map Model. The Digital Map is the first 
			step towards the Digital Twin. 
			
			The Digital Map Model and Data will provide this missing correlation 
			between the topology models and data and all other models and data: 
			KPIs, alarms, incidents, inventory (with UUIDs), 
			configuration, traffic engineering, planning (what if), 
			simulation, emulations, actions, behaviours.
			
			Some of these models and data are in the context of device, 
			some in context of network or subnetwork and some in context of 
			customer services, needed for both inner and outer closed-loops.
			
			Therefore, Digital Map is needed to break down data islands and 
			have a digital twin for simulation and closed loop, which is 
			required to solve autonomous networking.

			The following are some use cases that require Digital Map:
			</t>
			<ul>
				<li>
					Generic Inventory Queries 
				</li>
				<li>
						o	Service-> subservice -> resource
				</li>
				<li>
						o	Resource -> subservice -> service
				</li>
				<li>
					Intent/Service Assurance
				</li>
				<li>					
					Service E2E and Per-Link KPIs on the digital map (delay, jitter, loss)
				</li>
				<li>
					Capacity Planning
				</li>
				<li>
					Simulation
				</li>
				<li>	
					Closed Loop 
				</li>
			</ul>

		
	  </section>
	  <section anchor="other-ietf-activities">
		<name>Other Related IETF Activities</name>
		<t>
			The following standards are core for the Digital Map.
		</t>
			<ul>
				<li>
					IETF Network Model and Network Topology Model <xref target="RFC8345"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					A YANG Grouping for Geographic Location <xref target="RFC9179"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					IETF Modules that augment <xref target="RFC8345"/> for differenet technologies:
				</li>
				<li>
					o	A YANG Data Model for Traffic Engineering (TE) Topologies <xref target="RFC8795"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					o	A YANG Data Model for Layer 2 Network Topologies <xref target="RFC8944"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					o	A YANG Data Model for OSFP Topology <xref target="I-D.ogondio-opsawg-ospf-topology"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					o	A YANG Data Model for IS-IS Topology <xref target="I-D.ogondio-lsr-isis-topology"/>
				</li>
			</ul>

		<t>
			The Digital Map may need to link to the following models, some are already augmenting <xref target="RFC8345"/>,
			we need further investigation for each of these items:
		</t>
			<ul>
				<li>
					Service Access Point (SAP) <xref target="I-D.ietf-opsawg-sap"/>, 
                    augments 'ietf-network' data model <xref target="RFC8345"/>  by adding the
					SAP inventory
				</li>
				<li>
					SAIN <xref target="I-D.ietf-opsawg-service-assurance-architecture"/> and <xref target="I-D.ietf-opsawg-service-assurance-yang"/>
				</li>				
				<li>
					An Inventory Management Model for Enterprise Networks <xref target="I-D.wzwb-opsawg-network-inventory-management"/> 
					augments 'ietf-network-topology' with inventory information for node, link and termination-point. It also has UUIDs.
				</li>
				<li>
					Data Model for Lifecycle Management and Operations <xref target="I-D.palmero-opsawg-dmlmo"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					KPIs: delay, jitter, loss
				</li>
				<li>
					Attachement Circuits (ACs) <xref target="I-D.boro-opsawg-ntw-attachment-circuit"/> and <xref target="I-D.boro-opsawg-teas-attachment-circuit"/>
				</li>	
				<li>
					Configuration: L2SM <xref target="RFC8466"/>, L3SM <xref target="RFC8049"/>, L2NM <xref target="RFC9291"/>, L3NM <xref target="RFC9182"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					Incident Management for Network Services <xref target="I-D.feng-opsawg-incident-management"/>
				</li>
				<li>
					Transaction ID
				</li>
				<li>
					Etc?
				</li> 
			</ul>
		</section>
	 </section>
	 <section anchor="ditial-map-requirements">
	 <name>Digital Map Requirements</name>
	 <t>
		The following are the core requirements for the Digital Map:
	 </t>
	 <ol>
		<li>
			Basic model with Network, Node, Link, Interface
		</li>
		<li>
			Layered Digital Map, from physical network up to customer 
			service and intent
		</li>
		<li>			
			Open and Programmable Digital Map. This includes read / Write for Digital Map 
			(write important for future simulations and what if scenarios). Doing what-if 
            analysis requires the ability to take snapshots and to switch easily between them.  
            Because we have to distinguish between a change on the digital map for future simulation 
            and a change that reflects the current reality of the network.
		</li>
		<li>			
			Standard based Digital Map Models and APIs (e.g. based 
			on IETF Network Topology). Digital Map must provide 
			the standards APIs that provide for Read / Write and 
			queries. This API must also provide the capability 
			to retrieve the links to external data / models.  
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map Models and APIs must be common over different network domains
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must be multi-vendor
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must provide semantics for layered network 
			topologies and for linking external models/data
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must provide inter-layer and between layer 
			relationships
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must be extensible with meta data
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must be pluggable
			a)	 We must connect to other YANG modules for Configuration, 
			    Inventory, Intent Assurance (SAIN), etc
			b)	Not everything can be in YANG, we need to connect Digital Map 
			    YANG model with other modelling mechanisms, both southbound, 
				northbound and internally
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map must be optimized for graph traversal for paths. This means
			that only providing link nodes and source and sink relationships to 
			termination-points may not be sufficient, we may need to have the direct relationship
			between the termination points or nodes
		</li>
	  </ol>
	 <t>
		The requirements [1-6] are automatically fulfilled with RFC8345 and extensions.
		The requirements [7-8] are partially fulfiled, there may be need for some additional semantics.
		The requirements [9-11] will need some extensions to the RFC8345. 
	    In some cases for [10], the links are already sone by augmenting 'ietf-network' and 
		'ietf-network-topology'. For others, we need to add some mechanims to link the models and data.
	 </t>
	 <t>
		The following are the scope requirements for the Digital Map:
	 </t>
	 <ol>
		<li>			
			Digital Map should contain only topological information 
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map entities should contain only properties used to identify topological entities at different layers, 
			    identify their roles and topological relationships between them
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map should contain only topological relationships inside each layer or between the layers (underlay/overlay)
		</li>
		<li>
			Digital Map should only have links to other functional Digital Twin data and models.
		</li>
		<li>
			ACLs and Route Policies will be outside of the digital map, they would be linked to digital map
		</li>
		<li>
			Dynamic paths may either be outside of the digital map, part of traffic engineering data/models
		</li>
		<li>
			Provide capability for conditional retrieval of parts of digital map 
		</li>
		<li>
			Must support geo-spatial, temporal, and historical data
		</li>
	 </ol>
	 <t>
		The following are the arch requirements for the Digital Map:
	 </t>
	 <ol>
		<li>
			Scale, performance, integration
		</li>
		<li>
			Initial discovery and dynamic (change only) synch
		</li>
	  </ol>
	  </section>
	  <section anchor="digital-map-modelling-experience">
	  <name>Digital Map Modelling Experience</name>
		<section anchor="ietf-network-topology-approach">
		<name> IETF Network Topology Approach</name>
			<section anchor="ietf-network-topology">
			<name>IETF Network Topology </name>
			<section anchor="ietf-network-topology-te">
			<name>IETF Network Topology TE</name>	
			<section anchor="how-to-augment-generic">
			<name>How to augment for generic Digital Map extensions</name>
			<t>
				Approaches that we can take
			</t>
			</section>
			<section anchor="how-to-augment-specific">
			<name>How to augment for new technologies / layers</name>
			<t>
				Some guidelines and maybe example in the Anex
				Also, how the existing augmentation work with Digital Map?
			</t>
			</section>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section anchor = "what-is-not-in-basic">
		<name>What is not in the basic model</name>
		<t>
			The following are the <xref target="RFC8345"/> extensions needed for Digital Map modelling and APIs:
		</t>
		<ul>
			<li>
				Bidirectional links
			</li>
			<li>
				Multi-point connectivity (hub and spoke, full mesh, complex)
			</li>			
			<li>
				We may need additional supporting relationships: supporting for TP->Node,
				supporting for Node->Network
			</li>
			<li>
				More Network-related semantic is needed, for example:
			</li>
			<li>
				We modelled Tunnels ad Paths via <xref target="RFC8345"/> but we lost some semantics that is in RFC8795
			</li>			
			<li>
				We modelled all relationships via supporting, maybe extend with how underlay is done in RFC8795
			</li>
			<li>
				Relationship Properties
			</li>	
			<li>
				Subtypes
			</li>				
			<li>
				Layers/ sub-layers 
			</li>	
			<li>
				Some common roles: primary, backup, aggregation, hub, spoke
			</li>				
		</ul>
		</section>
		<section anchor="layering-open-issues">
		<name>Open issues for further analysis</name>
		<t>
			The following are the open issues that need further analysis:
		</t>
		<ul>
			<li>
				Do we need separation of L2 and L3 topologies?
			</li>
			<li>
				Do we need sublayers as well? Layers versus sublayers? E.g. Routing versus OSPF, IS-IS
			</li>
			<li>
				Same technology at service versus underlay? BGP per VPN vs common BGP shared 
				between multiple VPNs. Different layers, same model, relationship define the layer.
			</li>			
		</ul>
		</section>
		<section anchor="how-external-world">
		<name>How to connect to the external world</name>
		<t>
			How to connect to other YANG modules
		</t>
		<t>
			How to connect YANG models with other modelling mechanisms
		</t>
		</section>
		<section anchor="digital-map-apis">
		<name>Digital Map APIs</name>
			<t> 
				This will include hierarchical APIs for cross-domain figure, IETF YANG Based API 
				(read and write, change subscription and notify) and Query API
			</t>
		</section>
		<section anchor="digital-map-knowledge">
		<name>Digital Map Knowledge</name>
		<t>
			The following knowledge was needed to build digital map:
		</t>
		<ul>
			<li>
				Abstract IETF Entities and Relationships as in <xref target="RFC8345"/>
			</li>
			<li>
				<xref target="RFC8345"/> Augmentations for a)Layers/sublayers b)Entities (services and subservices),
				c)Properties
			</li>
			<li>
				Rules for aggregating entities
			</li>
			<li>
				Rules for instantiating relationships Relationships (inter-layer and intra-layer)
			</li>									
			<li>
				Mapping from devices and controllers
			</li>			
		</ul>
		<t>
			What can be achieved with existing RFC8345 YANG:		
		</t>
			<ul>
				<li>
					Entities (base class IETF Network, IETF Node, IETF Link, IETF TP)
				</li>
				<li>
					Properties
				</li>
				<li>
					Relationships
				</li>
			</ul>
		<t>
			Next steps
		</t>
		<ul>
			<li>
				How to add temporal
			</li>
			<li>
				How to add spacial
			</li>
			<li>
				How to add historical
			</li>
		</ul>

		</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	  
	<section anchor="Conclusions">
	  <name>Conclusions</name>
	  <t>
		Digital Map Modelling and Data are basis for the Digital Twin. 
		During our PoC we have proven that Digital Map can be modelled using <xref target="RFC8345"/>.
		Nevertheless, we proposed some extensions/augmentations to <xref target="RFC8345"/> to support Digital Maps.
		There must be some constraints in regards to how to augment the core Digital Map model for different 
		Layers and Technologies in order to support the approach in our PoC. All entities must augment IETF node, 
		IETF network, IETF link or IETF Termination Point and augmentation can only include new properties.
	  </t>
	</section>
	<section anchor="security-considerations">
	  <name>Security Considerations</name>
	</section>
	<section anchor="iana-considerations">
	  <name>IANA Considerations</name>
	  <t>
		This document has no actions for IANA.	
	  </t>
	</section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml"?>	  
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8345.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8346.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8944.xml"?>
    </references>
    <references title="Informative References">
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-irtf-nmrg-network-digital-twin-arch-02.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8795.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9179.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-ogondio-opsawg-ospf-topology-00.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-ogondio-lsr-isis-topology-00.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-ietf-opsawg-sap-15.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-boro-opsawg-ntw-attachment-circuit-02.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-boro-opsawg-teas-attachment-circuit-05.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-ietf-opsawg-service-assurance-yang-11.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-ietf-opsawg-service-assurance-architecture-13.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-wzwb-opsawg-network-inventory-management-01.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-palmero-opsawg-dmlmo-09.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.draft-feng-opsawg-incident-management-00.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8466.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8049.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9291.xml"?>
	  <?rfc include="http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9182.xml"?>
    </references>
    <?rfc needLines="100"?>
	<section numbered="false">
	  <name>Contributors</name>
	  <t>
		The following people all contributed to creating this document:
	  </t>
	</section>
    <section numbered="false">
	  <name>Acknowledgements</name>
      <t>
          Thanks to xx for their reviews and comments.
       </t>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
<!-- Local Variables: -->
<!-- fill-column:72 -->
<!-- End: -->